-I'm here to take you home.
-Move!
I can't do that.
What's going on?
I've been getting the headaches
since Andy left.
When I touch things,
they begin crumbling.
You're with the Purifiers?
I don't think
-I'm down to join a...
-Hate group?
The mutants that escaped
from the mental hospital
are dangerous. Show everybody
that the Purifiers
are part of the solution.
Come on,
the doc's ready for you.
Time for another exercise,
girls.
This is a bad man
with a secret.
I need you
to look inside his mind
and tell me what it is.
Don't make me ask twice, girls.
Please don't.
He's scared.
-He thinks you'll find
his family.
-And hurt them,
-because they're mutants.
-DDig deeper.
Tell me where they are.
He doesn't want
to think about it.
He doesn't want us to know.
Then work together,
just like we talked about.
Three minds in one.
Please don't make us.
He's so scared for his family.
You know the rules, Esme.
Do you care about his family...
or yours?
Please! Please don't!
They'll kill them!
Hey. Sorry, they, uh...
they need us in training,
like, now.
What, again?
We're training again?
Yeah. It's just
what the Frosts said.
They've had us running
through crazy simulations
nonstop all week.
What is it this time?
Attacking a armored
personnel carrier?
A citywide chase?
I heard something
about a SWAT team, actually.
Unreal.
This just keeps getting
better and better.
I think Reeva just wants to
prepare us for the next mission.
And where's she been lately?
She even in the building?
You know how she is.
Out doing important stuff.
Never talks about it.
Yeah, well, she better start.
So, does-does that mean
you're coming, or...?
'Cause Rebecca's
already down there.
Yes, I'll be there in a minute.
Okay.
Oh.
I'm sorry, baby girl.
Mama's got to work.
Yeah.
Hmm?
What about this one?
Everything has
to have sleeves now.
Ugh. I can't believe we have
to wear last season's look
because you let
that human flashlight grab you.
Hologram simulation active.
Open fire!
Get 'em!
Brava.
-Still needs work.
-I can do better.
I was slow with those guys
at the end there.
No, you were awesome.
Look who breezed in.
Is there something wrong, Lorna?
You tell me. We're training
for some mystery job
by playing
SWAT team Whac-A-Mole
with a bunch of holograms?
No need to be upset.
These are just
worst-case scenarios.
Last time we went out in the
field, we nearly got ambushed
by the Mutant Underground,
and now we're, what,
preparing to take fire
from all sides?
What the hell kind of mission
is this?
An important one.
Well, here's something
that's important to me.
My baby,
who I've barely seen in two days
because of all of this training,
who may notice if Mommy comes
home riddled with bullets.
I need to know the actual plan.
You'll know when you need
to know. Trust me.
We're all on the same side here,
Lorna.
Are we?
I'll make this real simple
for you.
Either tell me what this little
operation is or I'm out.
I don't see any more
signs of a concussion.
I am gonna go out on a limb
and pronounce you
-recovered.
-Thanks.
How's Dr. Kelsey?
It was a close call.
He'll be better by the time
the clinic reopens.
He's a bit rattled.
I can imagine.
On the bright side,
I was able to track down
the psychiatrist
that worked
at that mental institution
where you saw Andy.
I made us an appointment
for tomorrow.
-You really think
that's a good idea?
-Yeah.
She worked at that hospital
that locked up mutants.
Yeah, well, apparently,
she felt bad about
the way they were treated,
so she might be willing to give
us some information
on that girl
that Andy broke out.
And if she won't?
Hey, we have to try.
If we can find out why they
wanted that girl, Rebecca,
we are one step closer to Andy.
You sure you're gonna be okay
without me tomorrow?
I still think I should go.
Reed, you need to train.
We have to get your powers
under control.
The-the anxiety meds
aren't working
and the side effects
are getting worse.
-Can't we just change the dose?
-Honey.
I know you want this
to just go away,
but you have to deal with it,
not just drug it.
It's so difficult to explain.
When it happens, I-I feel
like I'm drowning.
Just like...
Like what?
It's like when I got sick
when I was a kid.
-When my dad made me sick.
-Hey.
It's like everything's happening
at once.
Just let John help you.
I don't see how training
can help.
It's just something
that happens.
Just try.
I remember you at law school.
You were good at learning
new things.
You're pretty damn good
at anything when you want to be.
You've always made me feel
like I can do anything.
You can.
You all remember Turner, here.
It was thanks to him we hit
that mutie clinic last week.
And he's been doing
a real good job
on some of the patient files
we found there.
Jace.
According to the files,
they were sending a lot
of their patients to a hospital
up in Baltimore,
but it turns out, some of 'em
never showed up.
The ones with arrest warrants.
You thinking Mutant Underground?
Who else can make mutant
fugitives disappear?
There's a station up there,
I guarantee it.
-Now...
-Yeah, so let's haul ass
up to Baltimore
and start shaking them trees.
-Boom.
Just listen up for a second.
Please. We need
to be smart about this.
These terrorists have stayed
ahead of the Sentinel Services
because they work the system.
They use our own society
against us.
Court orders, warrants.
One of them scurries
into a church,
suddenly they're untouchable.
Now, we don't have those rules.
We can flush 'em out,
run 'em to ground, tie 'em up
in a neat little bow
for the feds to collect.
So we just start doing
their jobs for 'em?
Let me ask you something,
guy who brings a .50-cal
to a meeting.
Why are you here?
Why are you all here?
'Cause I think it's for the same
reason that I'm here.
You want to make your
neighborhood safe again, right?
And I'd say that most people
agree with you.
But guess what.
Mr. and Mrs. PTA
don't want to be
on the same side
as a hate group.
And if you keep running around,
waving your guns,
beating up doctors,
that is exactly
how people see you.
They see you as a hate group,
but if you do this right,
they'll come running
to your cause.
Did I miss the part
where we put you in charge?
Hey! Settle down.
Here's how it's gonna be:
I've talked to leadership.
They want results.
We're gonna give this plan
a shot.
On my orders.
We clear?
Truth is,
it's time somebody solved
the mutant problem.
And it's going to be us.
I was hoping you'd come.
Andy, what is this place?
This is where we train.
You could have killed me.
I know. I'm sorry,
but I did warn you.
Just don't get in my way again,
okay?
This isn't you.
How could you hurt
your own family?
This is my family now.
And they're making me stronger.
-They could make you
stronger, too.
-Don't.
This doesn't have to be a war.
Aren't you sick of running?
The Inner Circle
is helping people.
So are we.
Do you really think that getting
a few mutants
to Mexico is helping?
Lauren, we can do things
that you can't imagine.
I thought you said
you could handle
training the team
while I was away.
We're sorry.
You knew how volatile Polaris
was when you recruited her.
I believe you said
we "needed her spirit."
Don't worry, we can bring her
back into the fold.
She's used to being a leader
in the Underground.
She doesn't like being left
in the dark.
None of us do.
I manage information
to protect all of us.
Of course.
But giving Lorna
a piece of the puzzle
isn't gonna threaten
the whole picture.
We asked her to join us.
And believe in our cause.
It seems we have a choice.
Trust her or lose her.
Fine. I have business I need
to take care of, so handle this.
Of course.
You can count on us.
And, girls...
Don't make me regret it.
I'm on my way.
Is everything arranged
on your end?
Good, because if anything
goes wrong,
suffice it to say
that the fallout from me
will be nothing compared
to the consequences for you.
-It's okay.
It's okay.
Mama's sorry
she hasn't been around much.
Shh.
Yeah, shh.
I finally got her to sleep.
She was screaming all morning.
We talked to Reeva.
I told you,
I'm not running blindfolded
into a slaughter.
And we're not asking you to.
We want to tell you the plan.
Really?
We have maps, route plans,
-blueprints of the target.
-When things go sideways,
blueprints are almost as useful
as to-do lists.
Look, I need to go there,
in person, to see it for myself.
I need to know what I'm risking
my life for.
Okay? I owe it to her.
Hmm.
All right, then.
We'll go.
Up till now, your powers
have manifested accidentally,
under stress.
When your emotions
are out of control,
your powers are out of control.
I'm not out of control.
I'm fine.
All right. Show me. Here.
Just... relax.
-Close your eyes and breathe.
How do you feel?
I feel like a guy
with his hand on a radiator.
Try and dig a bit deeper.
Can't you just show me
the technique?
Th-There's no one technique.
All right,
activating your powers,
it starts with what's going on
with you internally.
Okay,
try this.
Focus on a time
your powers manifested.
How you felt when you crashed
the car with Lauren.
-Dad!
Nothing's happening.
Reed, I can hear your heartbeat.
It's not even elevated.
I get it, Reed.
You want a shortcut, don't you?
You want to make up
30 years of experience
in one afternoon
without doing any work.
But to get a handle on this,
you have to face your fears.
I know you're scared
to think about memories
-that are too painful.
-That is not true.
Okay, you have another excuse
for me? You have another reason
-why you think you're special?
So you gonna tell me
you're in control right now?
Guys,
you got to see this.
Shatter called.
He just sent this.
Purifiers bombed
a sanctuary church in Baltimore.
-My God.
-They're bombing churches now.
I mean, that's a crazy big step,
even for them.
Yeah, they got a big group of
refugees who've lost everything
and no way to move 'em.
Shatter's gonna take in
as many as he can
at the Baltimore station,
but he needs our help.
They need IDs, cars, the works.
Yeah, well,
I checked police scanners.
The cops are out in full force.
It's not a good time to move.
Yeah.
That's why we have to go.
We have to show them
we're still here.
We have to stand together
with the Mutant Underground,
especially now.
It's too bad this is
what it takes to get
your ugly mugs up here.
Shatter, good to see you, too.
-Good to see you.
-So, what's the situation?
We got about 20 refugees
from the bombed church.
They've been filtering in
all day. And we already got
a full house to begin with.
Things have gotten worse
ever since that hospital attack
-last week.
-Uh, great.
The Inner Circle makes the
mess-- we get to clean it up.
Oh, it's worse than that.
The human groups
that used to help us,
they won't even take our calls.
We need to get the names
of the people who came in
and start making some new IDs.
I'll get my equipment.
We'll get on the names.
-You sure
you're okay to do this?
-Why?
-You think I'm gonna explode?
-Reed, you disintegrated
a cast-iron radiator earlier.
I was just... overwhelmed.
Look, I'm strong enough
to keep it together
while I make some IDs.
Reed, it's not
about being strong.
You're not gonna know
what's gonna set you off
until you deal
with the fear and the anger
-that's triggering this.
-You don't know anything
-about what I'm feeling.
-No, but you do.
And you need to own
those feelings
or you'll never have control
of this.
When your father suppressed
your X-Gene,
he also robbed you of the chance
to work through this
when you should have.
John, I appreciate it,
but I'll work through it
in my way.
We got all the personal
information we could.
Lots of these folks
have been living
in shelters and churches
for a while now.
Should be enough.
Let me see.
I heard a little of what
you was talking about with John.
-Yeah, well, that's not...
-Uh, no, just hear me out.
You know how I found out
I was a mutant?
I went to sleep one day
a normal kid,
and I woke up looking like this,
and everything I touched
was turning to crystal.
It was terrifying.
When I looked in that mirror,
I saw a monster.
So...
I tried to kill it.
I didn't put out the lights,
but...
I cracked the windows a bit.
I guess, sometimes,
the more you...
reject the things
you can't face,
the worse you make it.
Here you go.
Ugh, chamomile. Really?
Well, if you're gonna be a yoga
mom, you got to look the part.
You wanted to see the target.
There it is.
A bank?
It's not just a bank.
They've got
a mutant detection system.
We can't get close
without setting off alarms.
Now I get why Reeva
was having us train
-to take fire from all sides.
-Lorna,
this place was built
on mutant suffering.
Creed Financial started funding
mutant slavery in the '50s
in South America.
They pushed through anti-mutant
legislation in the '70s,
for slumlords in mutant ghettos.
And they spent the '90s
creating the Kick epidemic.
They've got their hands
in everything,
even local Purifier chapters.
But this, this is
exactly the kind of thing
you joined the Inner Circle for.
With all of Reeva's secrets,
how am I supposed to know
what anything's for?
You saw what happened
after we hit the hospital.
Hundreds of mutants
took to the streets.
We hit this place,
maybe thousands.
We'll inspire an army.
All right, look...
this one...
it's not just a cause.
It's personal.
For me
and my sisters.
Creed Financial funded the lab
that created us.
Created you?
My sisters and I...
we're clones.
They made us do
terrible things.
For years, it went on,
until we couldn't
take it anymore.
We stopped the guards before
they could put the collars on.
And we did what we had to do.
Fire. Fire. Fi-Fire. Fire.
We were 13 years old.
Fire.
We got out.
But we didn't escape
what they did to us,
the things they made us do.
I know it's a risk, Lorna,
but some risks are worth taking.
I think we have a problem.
What is it?
I spoke to a bunch of refugees
from the church
about what happened.
None of them were injured.
Isn't that a good thing?
Does seem kind of strange.
If a bunch of Purifiers bomb
a church to hurt mutants,
why were none of them hurt?
Because it's a trap.
We have to get everyone
out of here now.
I'll go get people
from the back now.
-Go, go.
-Too late.
They're here.
MAN:
Come on, let's do this.
We have you surrounded.
Anyone in the Mutant Underground
who wishes to surrender
will not be harmed.
You'll be handed over
to the proper authorities.
They don't seem disposed
to surrender.
They might.
Just... give it a few minutes.
-I say we storm the castle.
-We're not... we're not
storming anything.
We're not here for blood.
We're here for justice.
Calm down.
What's next, Jace?
Trigger fingers
are getting awfully itchy
around here.
Does it really matter
if we smoke 'em out
or just smoke 'em?
Yes, it matters!
Listen up and listen good.
The terrorists and the killers
are inside, not out here.
We're the good guys here.
Remember that.
we can count on you?
Still want to look over
the attack plan, but I'm in.
You were right, you know.
If we're gonna do this,
we need to trust each other.
I'm glad we did this.
Me, too.
But don't ever make me drink
chamomile again.
Where did you hear that song?
Uh, I don't know.
Just something
that got stuck in my head.
Probably from some old movie.
I don't think so.
That's the lullaby
I sing to my baby.
Oh, well, I, um...
I must've overheard it.
My aunt sang it to me
when I was a kid.
She learned it from my mom.
It's all I have from her.
I only sing it to Dawn
when we're alone.
Were you in my baby's head?
Lorna,
what are you talking about?
Answer me. When Dawn stopped
crying earlier,
was that you in her head?
No, I-I would never
do something...
-Don't lie to me!
-Uh, I didn't mean any harm.
She-she was upset, and I...
-Is this your idea of trust?
Is anything you tell me
even real?
Please, y-you...
you don't understand.
No, I understand. Nothing
-you say is real.
Please, Lorna,
-I can't breathe.
If you or your sisters so much
as look at my daughter again,
I will kill you.
-Sorry.
I couldn't let you do something
you'd regret.
Just keep your monsters away
from me and my daughter.
Esme, are you okay?
Dr. Taylor's office
is just up here.
Listen.
I want to talk to you
about what happened
with you and Andy
at the hospital.
I feel like
I pressured you to face him
when you weren't ready.
I keep telling you, Mom...
that wasn't your fault.
I just can't let go of the idea
that we can get through to him.
We had another dream last night.
You really think
he's having these dreams, too?
I know he is.
You wouldn't recognize him.
He's different.
He's gotten so much stronger.
I've been talking to John.
Andy getting stronger
isn't unusual.
Powers develop and-and change.
-Yours might, too.
-And then what?
Fight Andy again?
Hopefully,
it-it doesn't come to that.
He-he may come home when he...
-He's not coming home.
-Well, when he realizes
-what he's doing is wrong...
-You still don't get it.
Andy doesn't want to be saved.
He believes the Inner Circle
is helping people.
Mutants are calling them heroes.
Maybe he's right.
Maybe we're the ones
that need to be saved.
Thank you so much for seeing us
on such short notice,
Dr. Taylor.
Of course.
It's such a tragedy,
what happened at the hospital.
Tea?
Uh, sure.
Now, which patient
were you here about?
I don't think you mentioned.
Um, we were hoping
you could tell us what happened
to our cousin, a-a young woman,
her name's Rebecca Hoover.
She's... your cousin?
Uh, yes, um...
we haven't been close
with that side of the family
for a while.
It's just... now that we know
that the X-Gene is
in our bloodline,
we thought we should get
to know more about her, maybe
what she can do.
I, uh...
I'll tell you what I can.
I haven't worked at the hospital
for a while, of course.
Yes, and-and why did you leave,
exactly?
I had issues with the treatment
of some of the patients.
Any time people are committed
against their will,
it's a difficult situation.
Mm.
Why don't I go get my notes?
Something's wrong.
Lauren, I know
you don't like this...
No, it's not that.
She's scared.
-Why would she be scared?
-I don't know.
Hey, Lauren.
Yes, please, I need help.
-Now let's try this again.
Tell me... about Rebecca Hoover.
-Please, what do you want?
-We just need information.
I can't talk about my patients.
Patients?
You tortured those people.
I treated them as best
as I could.
Locking them in cages
like animals!
Hey, I know
you did the best you could.
I spoke to one of your patients.
Michael. Do you remember him?
He said you were kind to him.
That's why we came to you.
I tried,
but it wasn't up to me.
-I should have done more.
-Then help us now.
Michael said you felt bad
about how they treated Rebecca,
that she was abused
and-and locked up.
Some very dangerous people
took her,
and we need to find out why.
Because they also have my son.
Oh, God, I'm so sorry.
What?
I need to show you something.
We recorded all of our patient
sessions at the hospital.
We had to drug her.
Otherwise, she could just
turn her collar inside out.
The cops found that out
the hard way.
She has the ability
to twist things.
A sort of dimensional
manipulation.
This was after she first came.
We thought she was on her meds.
We were wrong.
I quit the hospital
the same day.
The autopsy said
she turned them inside out.
Oh, God.
That's how I knew
you weren't Rebecca's family.
That's how she killed them, too.
Talk about amateur hour.
Sloppy, sloppy, sloppy.
You started having feelings
all over the place
and let your guard down.
-I did what I had
to do to convince her.
-Yeah.
-She looked really convinced.
-I believe
the last thing I said to you was
"Don't make me regret it."
Don't worry.
We broke it, we'll...
-Fix it.
-We can't afford
to make any more mistakes.
We need Lorna
for this plan to work,
and we need her by tomorrow.
Well, we'll just have to use
a more... direct approach.
We can't control Lorna
like that, not forever.
Between the three of us,
we can do it long enough
to fix your mistake.
Controlling people's minds
can't be the solution
to everything.
Esme, that's what we do.
That's what we are.
No, that's what he wanted us
to be.
You said
we're building a new world.
But if we're gonna build
something lasting,
something real,
then people need to believe,
especially Lorna.
I admire your passion, Esme,
but we can't afford
to get sentimental.
We're all making
sacrifices here.
Hey, guys, grab your stuff
and let's go.
It's Jace Turner
again. He was at the clinic.
He must have tracked us here
somehow.
He's almost as good as you.
Look, if you can portal
everyone there,
we got a straight shot
to the road.
They're gonna notice when we
pop up behind them like gophers.
I don't know about you,
but I can't run faster
than a pickup truck.
Eclipse, Skyler,
and Naya can cover us.
Shatter and I will run
interference.
Hey, everybody, on my signal,
get ready to run!
I'm gonna open up a portal.
I need you guys to move through
as quickly as possible and seek
cover as fast as you can.
-Bomb!
-It's gas!
Everybody get out!
Run!
Get to the back of the building.
-Clarice. Clarice.
Come here.
Let's go, let's go.
-Move it! Drop down!
We have to go back
for the others.
We can't.
That is Halothane-X gas.
If you go back there, you'll be
unconscious in seconds.
Halothane-X?
Didn't the cops stop using that
after all those people
got trampled?
We're not dealing with cops.
We got to get out, man.
With those guys by the trucks,
we're sitting ducks.
-What do we do now?
-Is there another way out
of here?
There is,
there is a service tunnel
on that side of the building.
But it's on the other side
of the wall.
We use it to bring people in,
but we can't get to it
without going back through
the gas.
-I can help with the wall.
-Okay, well,
we're still gonna have to deal
with the guys outside.
Maybe I can take 'em out.
You can't go out there, man.
My body can handle most
small arms fire.
You sure?
This the only chance we got.
-All right.
-Okay.
Three, two...
Come on, come on.
Come on.
Whoa, whoa!
Get down!
Damn it.
Ray!
Oh, hey, kid.
Come on, Reed.
You can do this.
Look inside.
It's in you.
Don't make me do this!
Get on the ground!
ut you and Mom
have never once talked
about what it might mean for me
to have Andy come home.
He's your son.
Follow him now, go, quick!
Come on.
Go! Get her, get her.
I told you to stay the hell
away from us.
-Was I unclear?
-Look,
if you want to
tear my head off, fine.
Just please hear me out.
Um,
I-I should never have been
inside your baby's head.
-Yeah.
-She was crying,
and I needed to talk to you.
It was wrong, and I'm sorry.
But I felt something in her.
Something I've never
felt before.
The love of a mother.
I didn't have a mommy either.
That doesn't give you the right
to invade my child's mind.
No, it doesn't. I...
manipulated you
because we need you.
-Because that's what we do.
We... we make people do
what we need them to do.
That's--
that's why we were made.
That's no excuse.
You don't just have
to accept that.
We didn't.
You deserve to know
the whole story.
What are you talking about?
We didn't start off as triplets.
Esme, Phoebe, Sophie,
report for duty.
During our exercises,
they kept two of us locked up
as leverage.
Celeste and Mindee had
to stay back that day.
Grab your guns.
Fire.
When we decided to escape,
we thought we could
save everyone.
We were wrong.
Mindee and Celeste,
we couldn't get them out.
We never told anyone
that story before.
Not even Reeva.
I've felt death.
I was a part of my sisters
when they died.
I felt the pain
and the terror
like it was happening to me.
And I would do anything...
anything to protect
your daughter from that.
I'm sorry, I just...
I want you to know that, whether
or not you join this fight,
I'm on your side...
and hers.
You did it, bud.
Authorities rolled up
the whole station.
Biggest mutant bust in years.
Not how I wanted that
to go down.
Look, those were
some pretty words
about nobody getting hurt.
But that man who died knew
what he signed up for.
He died a hero,
and he'll inspire dozens more.
Want to make an omelet,
you got to some break eggs.
And that guy you cracked open?
Turns out, Humpty Dumpty
supposedly died in Atlanta.
You said your wife thought
you were chasing
some loony conspiracy theory?
Well, look at you now.
Come on.
The guys are buying rounds
of Patrón.
You're one of us now, brother.
Lauren, wait.
There's something
I need to tell you.
What, what is it?
I've been thinking, and I
realized, with this whole trip,
I am making the same mistake
as before,
dragging you into a fight
that is not yours.
Mom...
It is not on you
to bring Andy back.
It's on me.
Oh, God.
Honey, you know I love you
every bit as much
as your brother, right?
I-I would never put you at risk
to save him.
I know that.
But you saw the same thing
I did.
Andy thinks he's doing
the right thing.
But the Inner Circle recruited
that psychopath.
If he won't come back
on his own,
I have to fight him
and bring him back myself.
Out of my, out of my
Get out of my head,
out of my head
Yeah, we're high and low
You're dark at your worst
You're loved
and you're cursed
You're high and low,
you're high and low
Get out of my head,
out of my head
Yeah, we're high and low
'Cause you wanted love,
'cause you wanted
'Cause you wanted,
'cause you wanted love
'Cause you wanted
'Cause you wanted love,
'cause you wanted...
What's wrong?
Where's Reed?
Maybe it's best if you don't.
What?
Oh, God...
-Don't come any closer!
'Cause you wanted love.
It won't stop.
I can't make it stop.